<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Business Time and Attendance Software Blog - Zarlu</title>
 <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://www.zarlu.com"/>
 <updated>2013-03-29T00:41:26-07:00</updated>
 <id>https://www.zarlu.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Zarlu Blog</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Employee Time Management</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/employee-time-management"/>
   <updated>2013-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/employee-time-management</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;employee_time_managment&#39;&gt;Employee Time Managment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly do people mean when they say they need employee time attendance business software? How can an employee time attendance business software make a business better? What are the cons and the pros? These are all important questions to consider when thinking about installing time attendance software into your office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, when people say that they need attendance software they are essentially saying, “our company needs to keep better track of when our employees are on and off the clock.” There are many benefits to this type of software including the fact that, it will allow you to increase productivity. This is because employees will be very clear as to when they are on the clock versus, eating lunch. It will also help your company keep track of how many hours are wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, you may notice an employee or two taking an extra five to ten minutes during break times everyday. This can add up quickly to a full hour or more of lost work throughout the week. By being able to track this you now have the ability to talk with your employee and reinforce how they need to only take the allotted time for his or her breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software will also give you the ability to reward those who are doing well on the job. People who are clocking in early and staying late. This helps you have data by which you can reward the hardworking employee and set a standard of work ethic in your office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software is designed to bring transparency to your employees time off and raise morale in the office. It is an excellent tool to help manage free time and time that is productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about installing and employee time attendance business software in your office feel free to ask questions to our specialized team. We are aware of the best software on the market and we are prepared to help you increase your office productivity. Do not be afraid to start as early as today on making your office a better work environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Business Software</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/business-software"/>
   <updated>2013-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/business-software</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;business_software&#39;&gt;Business Software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless the business is a one man operation, such as a contractor or a proprietorship, chances are that we will have at least one or more employees. Keeping tabs on our employees can usually be handled through our payroll reports, which will in turn give us an idea about the length of time they have been on the job. If we can find computer software to handle that task for us, our lives would be so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payroll departments generally use paper methods to track the length of time the employee has been on the job, but those methods can be a problem to keep track of and can even be altered, depending on who wants to see the changes. Smarter business operators are turning to employee time attendance business software, where a whole lot more than just time can be tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking when an employee shows up for work, used to be a little more tedious than it is today. With the right computer program, an HR department can compile a list of dates and times, and other pertinent information. We can print and analyze reports which show how employees perform, based on whether they are continuously tardy, or whether they have a perfect attendance record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larger corporations with several departments, especially the ones looking for solutions to high labor costs, can establish which department is wasting man hours and which ones need to have their payroll increased. This used to be a very time consuming exercise, with business software, that is no longer the case. When it comes to scheduling and reducing overtime hours, the business should be able to see some financial improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a business manager, you should be looking for your employee time attendance business software to have features that help with productivity and reflect down time, monitoring stats by controlling intervals and linking hours and attendance to your payroll computer. With features like these, employers will be in a better position to determine where their weak spots might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future expectations of employee tracking have changed considerably, in fact payroll departments and the ability to manage our employees can now be defined by the kind of business software that we use. In order to provide optimum results when it comes to attendance and all other aspects of payroll and human resources, we are choosing to store our information digitally and not just when it comes to tracking attendance.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tracking Employee Attendance</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/tracking-employee-attendance"/>
   <updated>2013-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/tracking-employee-attendance</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;tracking_employee_attendance&#39;&gt;Tracking Employee Attendance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things that a business owner needs to know is whether his or her employees are showing up when they&amp;#8217;re supposed to. However, keeping track of employee attendance is one of the biggest, traditional administrative problems that a business can have. In fact it&amp;#8217;s often such an issue that entire departments of HR are assigned to cover it and make sure it&amp;#8217;s followed carefully. Fortunately, thanks to technology, there are now employee time attendance business software solutions that can be used to simplify and streamline this often tiresome administrative chore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;employee_time_attendance_business_software&#39;&gt;Employee Time Attendance Business Software?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is more expensive than just having employees write down their hours worked, time attendance business software is much more effective and reliable. Employers need to have computer terminals where employees can sign in, or they need to provide a method of identification and an electronic timeclock where employees can &amp;#8220;punch in&amp;#8221; to record their hours worked. Many businesses print ID badges for their employees which they can then swipe through the time clock, recording when they left and when they came back. The result is an automatic record that can be compiled with the push of a button to show exactly when employees showed up and on what days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;the_benefits&#39;&gt;The Benefits&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using employee tracking software is a no-brainer solution for businesses that want to simplify their attendance records. This software automatically creates records for hours, days, weeks, months and years, making it possible to practically automate attendance and payroll. Only when there are mistakes made do hours need to be inputted manually to reflect when a person actually worked. This reduces the amount of time and effort that goes into payroll, and it means that a smaller department is necessary to handle all of the employee monitoring efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;implementation&#39;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other advance used by employers, employee tracking software will take some time to get used to. Employees will have to be trained, and there will be some mistakes and problems as everyone gets used to the new way of doing things. However, that said, between free training and easy access it should never be an issue for either employees or employers who need to make sure that hours are correct at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Importance of Using a Time Attendance Program</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/importance-of-using-a-time-attendance-program"/>
   <updated>2013-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/importance-of-using-a-time-attendance-program</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;importance_of_using_a_time_attendance_program&#39;&gt;Importance of Using a Time Attendance Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of business, any business, is to run an efficient operation that has good revenue generation and controlled expenses. It is also imperative that employees perform their routine and required duties on a regular basis and all employee time is accounted for and logged properly. This is due to the fact that in terms of overhead and operating costs associated with business, employee wages and salaries are some of the highest reoccurring costs and thus need to be managed and monitored properly. One of the top ways to control employee hours and payments is through the use of employee time attendance business software that is designed to keep track of that aspect of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee time attendance business software allows for human resources and payroll operations to log employee hours worked, time off for sick, personal and vacation days and even account for overtime. This can then provide operations with a clear view of how many hours are being logged for a specified time period and thus used for budgeting and other financial decision making. It is highly difficult to track and monitor each and every employee without the use of automatic systems that help to keep manage employee time spent at and away from work. This type of software system can help with planned days off, unscheduled absences, hourly payroll rates and even budgeting for allowed overtime work. The various ways such systems can help keep tabs on employee costs can be highly beneficial for a business as they work towards become a better functioning entity and a leaner operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimal way to better control business operations is through the use of tools and technology that can assist with all of the functions and operations of a business so that clear reports can be viewed to gauge the health and well being of the business. The way to handle human resource functions that pertain to employee costs is through the use of such systems as employee time attendance business software that truly can help a business get a better handle on the hours worked by employees. This is one of the elements a business can easily and readily employ so that curbing and controlling costs, monitoring lost time due to employee absence and even employee performance based on work hours can be used as a way and means of creating a better business in general.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Human Resources Software Analysis</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/human-resources-software-analysis"/>
   <updated>2013-03-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/human-resources-software-analysis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;human_resources_software_analysis&#39;&gt;Human Resources Software Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wide range of software options are available for people that work in human resources and deciding on the right ones for a business can be critical. With employee time attendance business software you can get most tasks related to human resources done faster and more efficiently. Delegating these tasks to specific individuals can end up costing more in the long run than simply using this type of software. Many other versions of these products exist, and most offer a range of options for a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The products in question can save a lot of time and money in the long run for most businesses. If a company has a significant amount of overhead, costs can be lowered by using the right tools. These tools come in the form of automated software programs which run on most computers, and can get the job often done by people completed more efficiently and faster. The relatively low cost of these programs means that just about any business can afford them and keep the costs related to management low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The options that come with employee time attendance business software programs include the expected time keeping tools needed for most businesses, along with a suit of other tools that greatly increase productivity. Other programs available for companies include project management software, and even business overhead analysis tools that can be used to track your return on investment. Each one of these is custom tailored to specific needs and can generally be customize to your preferences so you only end up with what you truly need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need an in-depth overview of your business and the way it structures its management you can hire certified individuals that have a knowledge of the software. These people can teach you or your team the needed skills to operate the tools you have and how to use them effectively. You can of course learn it yourself, though with the help of these professionals you can often get the job done faster. Every business will have different needs so consult with your management to know what is needed.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Employee Scheduling Software</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/employee-scheduling-software"/>
   <updated>2013-03-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/employee-scheduling-software</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;employee_scheduling_software_accept_no_substitutions&#39;&gt;Employee Scheduling Software: Accept No Substitutions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees are the precious lifeblood of any business; it is imperative that they function in a timely, efficient, and cost effective manner to keep the enterprise running smoothly and the owner in good spirits. Finding the right employee time attendance business software can be daunting, but once you&amp;#8217;ve made the connection your company will gain the unabated momentum of a runaway freight train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal employee scheduling software would be one that saves time, keeps your employees upbeat, and makes shift informative data promptly ready. In the name of pragmatism, staff administration software should streamline the technique of dropping in employee informative data and shift necessities. It likewise ought to streamline your capacity to give every employee sufficient hours, plan employees to work just when they are accessible and guarantee that employees with the correct qualifications encompass every shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee time attendance business software is the holy grail for any business owner, manager, or even supervisor. A manager with a good head on his or her shoulders and a reputable copy of employee scheduling software at the helm is unbeatable; it helps bosses wring every second out of a daily routine quickly by making standard schedules sublime, mediocre plans multifarious, and by relegating shifts all without a moment&amp;#8217;s delay. A good schedule can replicate a calendar week after week, make modification for any special circumstances that may arise, and even adapt to irregular business hours. Employees can submit time-off solicitations electronically, and bosses can keep away from oversights and oversights by affirming time-off appeals, shift swaps and solicited hours straight in the booking software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that you&amp;#8217;re paying for a more refined piece of employee time attendance business software, you require it to do more than function as a meager timetable spreadsheet. Composing schedules ought to be a lion&amp;#8217;s share of informative data that you can utilize as a part of an multitude of ways. You require choices that gave you a chance to value employee positions, aptitude levels and needed hours. You moreover need characteristics that gave you a chance to relegate divisions and accessible by the manager to employees, let employees join open shifts and alarm you to booking clashes in time for you to resolve them. The choice is clear: accept only the finest in scheduling software today, and you won&amp;#8217;t be sorry tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Employee Attendance</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/employee-attendance"/>
   <updated>2013-03-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/employee-attendance</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;employee_attendance&#39;&gt;Employee Attendance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of business, any business, is to run an efficient operation that has good revenue generation and controlled expenses. It is also imperative that employees perform their routine and required duties on a regular basis and all employee time is accounted for and logged properly. This is due to the fact that in terms of overhead and operating costs associated with business, employee wages and salaries are some of the highest reoccurring costs and thus need to be managed and monitored properly. One of the top ways to control employee hours and payments is through the use of employee time attendance business software that is designed to keep track of that aspect of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee time attendance business software allows for human resources and payroll operations to log employee hours worked, time off for sick, personal and vacation days and even account for overtime. This can then provide operations with a clear view of how many hours are being logged for a specified time period and thus used for budgeting and other financial decision making. It is highly difficult to track and monitor each and every employee without the use of automatic systems that help to keep manage employee time spent at and away from work. This type of software system can help with planned days off, unscheduled absences, hourly payroll rates and even budgeting for allowed overtime work. The various ways such systems can help keep tabs on employee costs can be highly beneficial for a business as they work towards become a better functioning entity and a leaner operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimal way to better control business operations is through the use of tools and technology that can assist with all of the functions and operations of a business so that clear reports can be viewed to gauge the health and well being of the business. The way to handle human resource functions that pertain to employee costs is through the use of such systems as employee time attendance business software that truly can help a business get a better handle on the hours worked by employees. This is one of the elements a business can easily and readily employ so that curbing and controlling costs, monitoring lost time due to employee absence and even employee performance based on work hours can be used as a way and means of creating a better business in general.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing the activity feed</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/introducing-the-activity-feed"/>
   <updated>2013-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/introducing-the-activity-feed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;introducing_the_activity_feed&#39;&gt;Introducing the activity feed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m proud to announce the addition of a great new feature to our software. Over the past few days we have rolled out to all subscriptions of all plan levels an activity feed that gives our customers a great way to view how their company is using our software. The activity feed gives you a history of all the actions that are happening in your account in reverse chronological order. I have leveraged the software feature infinite page scrolling into our activity feed, so that you can view activity as far back as the creation of your account without clicking through pages or even refreshing the page. All your account activity is transparently visible to you our customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity feed has three different sections available to your employees. The default and first view is a look into the signed in employee&amp;#8217;s activity. For example, if you are signed in you will be able to view a history of all the time off requests you have submitted or changed since you joined Zarlu. The second view gives managers a look into all activity for each of the employees that they are managing time off requests for. The manager view gives managers a quick and easy way to see if co-workers have added time off that they (the manager) need to approve or reject. It also has the benefit of keeping managers updated with all of the schedules they are responsible for managing. The final view gives employees a view of all time off and schedule changes throughout their company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the activity feed for yourself by signing in to your subscription. The link is on the top of every page in the navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>10 countries with the most employee time off</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/10-countries-with-the-most-employee-time-off"/>
   <updated>2013-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/10-countries-with-the-most-employee-time-off</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;10_countries_with_the_most_employee_time_off&#39;&gt;10 countries with the most employee time off&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every country has its own set of labor laws governing how many days an employee is minimally guaranteed to use for time off. The United States does not have a minimum set at the federal level for time off, but many state and local governments have their own minimums amounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most US employees who do receive time off have about 8 national holidays and 10 non-specified &amp;#8220;floating&amp;#8221; days to be used anytime during the year. Many of the countries in the top of this list mandate a minimum time off day due to generous labor laws. For example, the European Union requires its members to have at minimum 20 days of employee time off in addition to national holidays. When looking at the top ten list below it is apparent how government laws can impact an employee&amp;#8217;s benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#39;paid_time_off_with_10_years_tenure&#39;&gt;Paid Time Off with 10 years&amp;#8217; tenure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;1_44__finland&#39;&gt;1. 44 - Finland&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;2_40__morocco&#39;&gt;2. 40 - Morocco&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;2_40__france&#39;&gt;2. 40 - France&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;2_40__israel&#39;&gt;2. 40 - Israel&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;2_40__lithuania&#39;&gt;2. 40 - Lithuania&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;6_39__united_arab_emirates&#39;&gt;6. 39 - United Arab Emirates&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;7_38__austria&#39;&gt;7. 38 - Austria&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;7_38__estonia&#39;&gt;7. 38 - Estonia&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;7_38__malta&#39;&gt;7. 38 - Malta&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#39;10_37__greece&#39;&gt;10. 37 - Greece&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://money.cnn.com/2007/06/12/pf/vacation_days_worldwide/#table&#39;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finland leads the list with an average of 44 days of employee time off for employees with at least 10 years of tenure. A huge difference from the United States which averages 25 days of employee time off. This total is the average vacation days for employee in the country specified including national holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Types Of Employee Time Off</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/types-of-employee-time-off"/>
   <updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/types-of-employee-time-off</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;types_of_employee_time_off&#39;&gt;Types of employee time off&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this diverse society we live in, more employees are requesting, and often receiving, additional time off work. A typical worker may want to schedule time off for a variety of personal reasons. Some companies are turning to tracking software to schedule time requested off by each employee to avoid calendar confusion and complications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common time requested off involves traditional holidays. New Year&amp;#8217;s, Martin Luther King Day, Presidents Day, Memorial Day, Independence Day, Labor Day, Columbus Day, Thanksgiving, and Christmas are the most common calendar days when employees expect not to work and yet be paid. Not every business will pay for holidays like Martin Luther King Day, Presidents Day, and Columbus Day, however, as those have more of a historical or political connotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some workers request time off as sick days. These are usually counted against an attendance record. A business might count two hours of work a person takes off for a doctor&amp;#8217;s visit as part of a sick day. Tracking partial days can be tricky, which is why a software program can be so helpful in monitoring attendance. Taking whole or partial days off for a sick spouse or child is usually counted as the employed person&amp;#8217;s sick day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies will track time taken to arrive late or leave early, whether or not a timecard is used. Long lunches may be deducted from the workday total, as well. Rather than track these detailed scheduling adjustments manually, it is easier to plug the numbers into a computer application and let it tabulate the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally a worker may request a day off for an uncommon event, like a child&amp;#8217;s school activity, music recital, or sports competition. These activities will need to be designated as an acceptable category in order for the employed person to be paid. Otherwise these absences may be considered as &amp;#8220;personal days,&amp;#8221; which some companies recognize and pay for, while others do not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding who gets paid for which absences, and who will not be paid, needs to be spelled out in company policy. The right computer program can make sure every minute of every workday for every worker is accounted for and paid accordingly. This is an important function with the company, as unpaid workers tend to become unhappy workers. If there is a misunderstanding about company policy, it should be ironed out as soon as possible. Employees&amp;#8217; attendance and absenteeism can be managed competently with a professional computer application.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Common Employee Vacation Time Off Holidays</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/common-employee-vacation-time-off-holidays"/>
   <updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/common-employee-vacation-time-off-holidays</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;common_employee_vacation_time_off_holidays&#39;&gt;Common Employee Vacation Time Off Holidays&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more challenging issues associated with human resources and even management planning is the time off employees routinely take for sick days, personal days and planned vacations. Though it can be challenging to plan accordingly for those unexpected days off; vacation is another issue and one that can greatly benefit by the use of tracking software that helps to monitor, manage and organize blocks of time off that employees have requested for vacations. This can be an essential planning tool for those firms where having too many people scheduled or slated to be gone at the same timeframe becomes a negative factor in terms of business operations or productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendance at work is a routine part of being a model worker and this is why the majority of people make sure to give advance notification when they are in the midst of planning their summer or vacation schedules. This is usually done manually by the employee as they look at their own personal calendar and determine the best days or weeks for them and their family to travel. One of the issues that tends to arise in the workplace is that certain and specific months of the year are more suitable and preferred for vacation and thus when a firm utilizes a tracking program to monitor requested vacation days; issues of too many people being out during the same week or day can be avoided or even staved off well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software that monitors attendance and also keeps a log of time off can be programmed to alert users when more requests than normal are being submitted. This can then be used to have discussions to help determine who will be allowed to have off and during what time periods. This is an essential function in business as enough workers need to always be present for all functions of the business to operate in the most appropriate manner. The ability to track request and track approvals can then be helpful in making decisions regarding any additional requests that are made by others. The overall impact is one that helps with operational and personal schedule conflicts and preferences which is beneficial to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of such advanced scheduling tools can alert those in charge of approving or scheduling vacations for others as they can use the calendar functions to predetermine holidays and preferred times of the year when many tend to use their vacation time to take off from work. This tool can then further be used to monitor those requests as they come in and are subsequently approved so that any additional requests can be promptly denied or discussed so that everyone always has the chance to take the vacation they want and deserve; yet preserve the operational integrity of the organization simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>When To Take Sick Days</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/when-to-take-sick-days"/>
   <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/when-to-take-sick-days</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;when_to_take_sick_days&#39;&gt;When to take sick days&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sick days have a complicated relationship with employers and employees alike. It&amp;#8217;s almost impossible to find an employee that will not occasionally call in sick for a personal reason, and there are many staff members that make it a habit. In order to adjust to this, most employers have to accept that sick days will sometimes be used as time off. By tracking their staff&amp;#8217;s attendance with tracking software, managers can avoid letting their staff take advantage of their good faith and make sure that these situations don&amp;#8217;t leave them in a bind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies give their staff both paid time off, and sick days. These are usually accrued by the paycheck based on the hours that the employees have worked, so it can be difficult to keep track of which staff members are still owed what hours. Paid time off is usually used as a staff member&amp;#8217;s vacation time. A good schedule tracking software will make it easy for a business to pull up a staff member&amp;#8217;s attendance and see exactly what hours they are due and if they are going in excess of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the staff member&amp;#8217;s side, while it may be easy to claim some free time by pretending to be sick, it isn&amp;#8217;t a good habit to get into. Because nearly every business does track their staff&amp;#8217;s schedule, managers can see if a staff member is establishing a trend of being sick more than they should be. This type of action will shake a manager&amp;#8217;s faith in their staff, and they may begin to ask for medical slips and paperwork before accepting any more sick leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sick leave is right to take any time a staff member feels that for medical reasons they will be incapable to do their job. This does include any medical procedures that are necessary for their health, their recovery, and any various illnesses that may come up such as the flu. It does not include other personal reasons, such as sleeping in late or being ill from a previous night out on the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendance software can be an invaluable way of identifying problem staff or seeing staff that may be having issues that are consistently conflicting with their ability to do their job. Because a business can simply pull up a calendar and see a staff member&amp;#8217;s entire history, it&amp;#8217;s easy to find patterns that are causing problems. And, while staff may not consider this, many managers will notice if the calendar shows that the staff member only seems to call out directly before or after a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sick days are earned by staff members with the hours that they put into the company, which means that they are truly entitled to these hours when they need them. Any staff member that is truly ill or has medical problems that need to be taken care of should never feel guilty taking a sick day. That said, even though they are earned, they are earned for a specific purpose and need to be used for only that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Pros And Cons Of Unlimited Time Off Policies</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/pros-and-cons-of-unlimited-time-off-policies"/>
   <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/pros-and-cons-of-unlimited-time-off-policies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;the_pros_and_cons_of_unlimited_time_off_policies&#39;&gt;The Pros And Cons Of Unlimited Time Off Policies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlimited time off policies have recently started trending as many companies have found it a good way to motivate their employees during the time that they&amp;#8217;re there. There are positives and negatives to this type of policy that need to be considered before a business decides to use it. Since it is such a radical shift from the traditional time off schedule it can be difficult for both employees and companies to adjust to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an unlimited time off policy, a business does not track their staff&amp;#8217;s vacation days or attendance, but rather let&amp;#8217;s them take their personal time when they choose. This means that the staff no longer have to worry about looking towards the calendar when they want to schedule a vacation, they simply have to tell the company or log something into the tracking software. The company can still, if they choose, mark off some days on the calendar as mandatory for attendance&amp;#8211;for instance, a particular busy season when they make the most sales or have the highest client volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For companies, this type of policy allows them to forgo tracking attendance and leave everything up to their staff member&amp;#8217;s discretion. Software can still be used to track their staff&amp;#8217;s working hours and, if necessary, billable time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some companies may believe that their staff would take advantage of the policy, companies that have initiated it haven&amp;#8217;t found any problems. Contrary to this, they&amp;#8217;ve actually found that their staff tend to be more motivated towards work. Even though the staff can take as many vacation days as they choose, they still need to fulfill their work duties. It&amp;#8217;s this need to fulfill the work duties and keep everything operating smoothly that calls them back to the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A policy like this puts emphasis more on accomplishments and not hours put in. Many of the hours that a staff member puts in when they don&amp;#8217;t feel motivated are actually wasted hours. By putting an emphasis on accomplishments, this pushes the staff members to focus on achieving goals and completing projects and not simply running down the clock. That said, these policies have been largely tested on staff members that have a high degree of accountability and control over their work, rather than entry-level positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether an unlimited vacation policy would work for your company is based on your company and staff&amp;#8217;s culture. If your staff are generally happy, motivated, and eager to get the job done then an unlimited vacation policy will probably increase productivity. It can also be used along with flex-time to offer a truly customized work experience. While unconventional, such a system allows trusted staff members to work when they know they will be the most effective, and take their hours and days when they know they feel unmotivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a system does carry out unlimited vacation days, however, the company does need to have a firm system of monitoring whether projects are being completed the right way and by the deadlines. Otherwise there will be no way of judging the increased efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Overcoming Peer Pressure To Not Take Vacations</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/overcoming-peer-pressure-to-not-take-vacations"/>
   <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/overcoming-peer-pressure-to-not-take-vacations</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;overcoming_peer_pressure_to_not_take_vacations&#39;&gt;Overcoming peer pressure to not take vacations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common problem that employees often face today with their time off is the inability to take a vacation without feeling guilty. This guilt can come from peer pressure, supervisors, or even themselves. Employees need to overcome this fear and take their vacations on the proper schedule without feeling as though they are doing something wrong. Every business knows that staff need their own time to rest, recover, and get ready for a productive year, which is why they track and watch these vacation days appropriately. On the company side of things, many employers need to watch how they treat vacations and consider whether they may add to an atmosphere that makes people nervous to take them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the schedule tracking software that your business provides may make it easier to take a vacation without a guilty conscience. You can pull up a calendar with your supervisor and track the projected attendance of your coworkers. By doing this, you can adjust your time off to correlate with an area on the calendar that attendance is high. Once you&amp;#8217;ve done this, you don&amp;#8217;t need to feel guilty or as though you&amp;#8217;re leaving the rest of your office short-staffed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s important for every staff member to recognize that their vacation days are not a gift but rather earned with the hours that they work. Vacation is as much a part of what a business owes their staff as their actual salary, and often extra vacation time is used instead of higher salaries. And even though other staff members may cringe when you talk about taking your vacation, they&amp;#8217;re often all too eager to take theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses need to take care not to cultivate an atmosphere where people feel as though they&amp;#8217;re being discouraged from taking a vacation. This means not meeting requests for vacation time with reluctance. If the company is tracking their staff&amp;#8217;s vacations with the right software it should be a trivial matter for them to keep everyone on a good schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ease vacations, businesses can start a transparent system whereby the staff can use areas of the tracking software themselves so that they can see on their own when the best days would be to take a vacation without upsetting anyone else. This will allow staff members to consider their plans without feeling awkward or guilty about it. It is far preferable to a company that staff members do their scheduling in advance, because otherwise they may wait until last-minute and make things difficult to adjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While vacation is earned, most companies today do not let it accrue past a certain point. Some companies will allow you to cash out your vacation days, but many won&amp;#8217;t. This means that if you do not appropriately take your vacation days, you may lose it completely. If you truly feel that your fellow staff will be adversely affected by your vacation days, you should sit down with your supervisor and discuss it. There may be a solution that does not involve you missing out on the vacation that you have earned.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Creating The Best Time Off Tracking Software</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/best-time-off-tracking-software"/>
   <updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/best-time-off-tracking-software</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;time_off_tracking_software&#39;&gt;Time off tracking software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time off tracking software should be as easy to use and simple as possible. You shouldn&amp;#8217;t have to think about how to submit a time off request. It should be as simple as possible so that you can work on the tasks that need your attention. At Zarlu, I have designed in my opinion the best software for tracking employee time off requests. Each of your employees will receive a subscription to Zarlu when you sign up for an account, and they will be able to use our fully functional calendar, scheduler, and notification system to easily manage their work schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;easily_approve_time_off_requests&#39;&gt;Easily approve time off requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to developing easy to use software for employees, I focused on developing an intuitive software application for managers and human resources to easily manage employee time off requests. What good is a great employee system if managers and human resources can&amp;#8217;t manage time off requests efficiently? At Zarlu, I thought about what would be best for your account from inception to daily use. The first step was to create a way to setup your account and to group employees by the manager or human resources personnel responsible for approving an employee&amp;#8217;s schedule and calendar changes. To solve this Zarlu provides an easy drag and drop interface for you to enter and group up to 150 employees without having to even change pages! Zarlu&amp;#8217;s setup is incredibly easy. Simply add an employee, which only needs an email and temporary password, and then drag them underneath the employee who will approve or reject their time off requests. It&amp;#8217;s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;email_time_off_requests&#39;&gt;Email time off requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took simplifying submitting time off requests beyond what other time off tracking software offers by allowing any employee to submit a time off request without even signing into Zarlu. In fact, the staffer does not even have to have a web browser open. To send a time off request, simply send an email to timeoff@mail.zarlu.com with a subject in the MM/DD/YY or MM-DD-YY format and we will add time off request directly to the employee&amp;#8217;s calendar and notify the manager or human resources employee to approve or reject the request. The employee can also add a message in the email&amp;#8217;s message field to give an explanation for the request to the employee from your company who is tracking time off requests. No need to submit a time off request through a website and then send an email to a manager. We do both tasks at once whether you are logged into www.zarlu.com or sending an email from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I have given you a helpful walk through of our time off tracking features. Feel free to contact me by clicking on the support link above if you have any questions about time off tracking or any other features of Zarlu. Click on the link below to get started with one of our free or paid plans if you haven&amp;#8217;t already. Our free plan has no time limit and requires no credit card, which gives you the freedom to make sure Zarlu fits your needs!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Zarlu Employee Calendar and Scheduler Goes Live</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/zarlu-employee-calendar-and-scheduler-goes-live"/>
   <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/zarlu-employee-calendar-and-scheduler-goes-live</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;zarlu_employee_time_off_tracking_software&#39;&gt;Zarlu Employee Time Off Tracking Software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of hard work, I am proud to officially announce the release of Zarlu. I started working on Zarlu after experiencing the frustration of submitting time off requests using traditional employee scheduling software. I found their software to be clunky, dated, and hard to use. Submitting a time off request should be easy. Viewing my schedule for a month, week, or day should be easy. Having a calendar to view my schedule is a requirement for a great personnel scheduler. I decided I could design a web application that made taking time off a better experience for the employee and the business. I wanted something better then what currently exists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Zarlu, I tried to make a scheduling application that I would want to use on a daily basis. My top three priorities were ease of use, speed, and convenience. For speed, Zarlu was developed using the latest web development techniques to allow pages and information to load as quickly as possible. The majority of Zarlu is rendered on our server &amp;lt; 100ms. Yes, you read that right. I measure your time in milliseconds because that&amp;#8217;s how much I care about devlivering excellent software. Sub 200ms response times are synonomous with &amp;#8220;instant&amp;#8221; in the software industry. With Zarlu, you will never have to wait around staring at a spinner or indefinite progress bar while your computer &amp;#8220;thinks&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my top three priorities for Zarlu, I also mentioned conveience. I have developed a feature that allows you to send a time off request directly from your email account whether on your phone at the top of a ski slope, on your iPad laying in bed while recovering from the flu, or on your notebook at work. No logging in required. Just email us at timeoff@mail.zarlu.com with your work email and we will add your time off request to your calendar and notify your manager to approve or reject your request. That&amp;#8217;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, ease of use was my third goal in my trifecta of priorites for developing calendar and scheduler software. I have developed our calendar to use a simple drag and drop interface to make modifying or adding events as simple as possible. Need to extend an event on your calendar? Simply click on it and drag your mouse to the desired time. Zarlu will save the event to your schedule when you let go of the mouse. How easy is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing your feedback of what Zarlu can do to make scheduling even easier for you! Click on the link below to try Zarlu for yourself if you haven&amp;#8217;t already. Our lowest plan is free to use with no time limit!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How Does Zarlu Secure My Data?</title>
   <link href="https://www.zarlu.com/how-does-zarlu-keep-my-data-safe"/>
   <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.zarlu.com/how-does-zarlu-keep-my-data-safe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 class=&#39;center&#39; id=&#39;how_does_zarlu_secure_my_data&#39;&gt;How does Zarlu secure my data?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past few years there has been a movement to move data from local computers into the cloud. Cloud Storage provides many benefits: it can be accessed from multiple devices, your data can stay synced between machines, and cloud providers are a backup for your data. One downside to cloud applications is that the user is giving up control of their data and trusting a 3rd party vendor to keep their data safe. As a cloud web application, I designed Zarlu to be worthy of your trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;ssl&#39;&gt;SSL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look in the url of your web browser. Do you the prefix https:// instead of http://? Zarlu uses SSL on every page of our application to ensure that your activity on Zarlu is encrypted. This is the same encryption used by banks for their web pages. Zarlu uses a 256 bit encryption algorithm to encrypt your data when we send it to you. Many browsers represent this connection with a padlock icon to notify you that your connection is secure. Many websites do not encrypt even their log in form, which means that if you log on to their software from a public place (Starbucks, airport, etc) a hacker can steal your username and password. By using SSL for our forms, we protect you from this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;payment_information&#39;&gt;Payment Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you decide to use one our wonderful paid plans, Zarlu asks you for your credit card so that we can charge you for the plan you selected. When you fill out the credit card form and hit submit, your credit card information goes directly to our payment provider &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.stripe.com&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;. Stripe handles all your payment information and then lets us know that your account has been paid for. We then store your last 4 digits of your credit card only so that we can show you which credit card of yours Stipe has on file in case you wish to change cards for a future payment. Your credit card number, security code, expiration month, and expiration year never even touch our servers. We send this information directly to Stripe using the https protocol that encrypts your information when we send it to Stripe. Https is the same protocol used by banks. We don&amp;#8217;t even log your credit card info. Zarlu does this because Stripe handles payment security at the most stringent level possible. They are certified as a PCI Service Provider Level 1 the highest level possible and are used by thousands of applications for their commitment to security. By using Stripe, Zarlu is also PCI compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;password&#39;&gt;Password&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of all the recent high profile security breaches where users passwords have been stolen? Many websites store your password simply as plain text, which means in their data if your password is 123456 then their data says your password is 123456. Software can never be perfect, so to protect this we encrypt your password. So if there is ever a security breach on Zarlu, when the attacker looks at your password they will see something like fdlksjfferr98weurwiewf instead of 123456. You many have noticed that our login forms say pass phrase instead of password. We want to encourage you to use a phrase or even a sentence instead of a single word. It is much harder for someone to guess &amp;#8220;My son&amp;#8217;s name is John, and I love going hiking with him!&amp;#8221; then &amp;#8220;password1&amp;#8221;. Keep that trick in mind for other passwords as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;software&#39;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zarlu uses several programming languages and frameworks to give you the best scheduling experience. I check for any updates, bug fixes, or patches on a daily basis to ensure that our software is secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;data_backups&#39;&gt;Data Backups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your plan level, we either backup your data on a weekly or daily basis. If something goes wrong on our end (server failure, etc), we have a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this page has given you a better understanding of how much we value the security of your information here at Zarlu. If you have any additional concerns feel free to contact us by clicking on the support link. If you have detected any security vulnerability in the Zarlu software, please click on support and let us know! Good deeds are rewarded!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
